如果您从未见过请求动画框架，那么这一问题很有挑战性。
This one is challenging if you've
never seen a request animation frame.
所以如果没别的的话那就是一个很好的例子
So, if nothing else, it's a good example
of how you'd move something smoothly
你可能要做的就是做一个 UI 工程师
into the dom which is something you would
probably have to do as a UI engineer.
让我们从这个功能开始。
So let's start with this function.
我们会把它叫做动元件
And we'll call it move elements.
这需要持续的时间。
And it takes the duration.
它有一个距离，它是一个元素。
Takes the distance, and
it takes an element.
好吧这次我们不回来了
Okay, in this one we're not returning
因为这不是这个功能的关键
anything necessarily because that's
not the point of this function.
我们所做的一切都将会更新我们的天地
Everything we do is
going to update the dom.
它会更新元素本身
It's gonna update the element itself.
所以我们实际上不需要归还任何东西。
So we don't actually
have to return anything.
但在这种情况下我想用请求动画来呼叫
But in this case,
I wanna use request animation to call
元素，找出该元素所在的位置，以及
the element,
find out where that element is, and
然后根据我要移动的持续时间逐渐地移动它。
then move it incrementally based on
the duration that I wanna move over.
所以我要做的第一件事就是呼叫请求动画的框架
So the first thing I'm gonna do is I'm
gonna call request animation frame.
这也是窗口上可用的功能。
Which again, is a function that
is available on the window.
所以，如果你进入控制台，输入请求动画帧，
So it's there, if you go in your console
and type request animation frame,
它会弹出来的
it'll pop right up.
我想搬动
And I wanna start off by moving.
我想叫这个功能
I wanna call this function.
我要给它打个电话然后给它打电话让我们在这里创造创意
I'm gonna call this function in and
we'll call it, let's get creative here,
我们会叫它动
we'll call it move.
这就是我的工作，这就是所有逻辑的所在。
And this is my workhorse,
this is where all the logic is gonna be.
requestAnimationFrame 只是回调，如果您愿意，或者
requestAnimationFrame is just a callback,
if you will, or
移动在技术上是一个回调。
move is technically a callback.
那么 requestAnimationFrame ，我们将对此进行调用。
So requestAnimationFrame,
we're gonna call move on this.
因此，这将首次调用此函数。
So this will invoke this
function the first time around.
我想做的就是因为我正在移动一段时间
And what I wanna do is because I'm
moving something over a duration,
我们会说 const.
we'll say const.
我们会得到开始时间等于绩效。
We'll get the start time
equals performance.now.
您也可以执行新日期。
You can also do new date.
这并不重要。
It doesn't really matter.
我喜欢 performance.now 的语法很短。
I like performance.now cuz
it's pretty short in syntax.
这会给我这个动画开始的时间
That's gonna give me the time
that this animation started.
当 requestAnimationFrame 调用函数时，
When requestAnimationFrame
calls a function,
它还会传递到高分辨率 DOM 时间戳记。
it also passes in
a high-resolution DOM timestamp.
这是事实的真实名称，等等。
That is the actual name of the thing,
wait.
我能看到人们不相信我
I can see people don't believe me.
让我们看看高分辨率的时间戳
Let's see, high-resolution timestamp.
看它是真实的 Dom High Res 时间戳记
See it's a real thing,
Dom High Res Time Stamp.
我不知道那里有一些怀疑论者我知道
I don't know,
there's some skeptics out there, I know.
但我们知道它会在某个地方
But, we know that it's
gonna be somewhere along
在准确性和移动方面未知的性能线。
the lines of performance unknown in terms
of accuracy and in terms of moving.
因为 requestAnimationFrame 几乎总是用于动画某些东西。
Because requestAnimationFrame is almost
always used to animate something.
所以我要说时间戳记，我们现在就叫它。
So I'm gonna say Timestamp,
we'll call it current time.
好的，我想到这个问题的下一个方法是什么 ?
Okay, what's the next way
I think of this problem?
那么 requestAnimationFrame 将调用一次移动。
Well, requestAnimationFrame
is gonna call move one time.
然后就这样了
And then that's it.
因此，我们需要 requestAnimationFrame 再次调用移动。
So we need requestAnimationFrame
to call move again.
所以它会一直自我定位直到满足某些条件
So it's gonna keep referencing
itself until some condition is met.
所以我想用一个 if 语句把它包起来因为我们不希望它持续
So I wanna wrap this in an if statement
because we don't want it to continually
一次又一次地打过去
call over and over and over again.
我们会说如果有什么事我们会回来的
We'll say if something,
we'll come back to that.
好吧好吧
All right.
现在我们有了一个动画循环。
So now we have an animation loop of sorts.
它什么都没做但它会自打过去
It's not doing anything, but
it will call itself over and over and
再次转移到元素中
over again to move in elements.
下一步我们想做什么 ?
What do we want to do next?
我们想把它的元素右移。
We want to actually
move the element right.
我们如何在 JavaScript中做到这一点 ?
And how would we do that in JavaScript?
我们可以说 elements.style。
We can say elements.style.
我们会改变我们的地位我们要翻译 x
And we're gonna run a transform equals,
we're gonna wanna translate x.
我们要把它移动一段距离
And we're gonna wanna
move it some distance.
所以，我们还没有真正了解到距离，所以我要把它留空。
So, we don't actually know the distance
yet, so I'll leave that blank.
这将以像素为单位。
And that's gonna be in pixels.
这听起来很熟悉吗
This sounding familiar to anybody?
你已经做过了你可能是在 CSS里做的
You've done it,
you've probably done it in CSS.
用 JavaScript 来做是非常相似的，只是不同的名字。
Doing it in JavaScript is very similar,
it's just different names of things.
现在你是警察了你都挂在里面了
Now you're troopers,
you're all hanging in there.
好吧，这就是数学进来的地方，这不好听，我开玩笑的。
All right, this is where the math comes
in and it's not pleasant, I'm kidding.
这只是你怎么想的方法
It's just a way of how you think about it.
所以给出一个时间，距离，时间，我们怎么计算，
So given a duration, distance, and
time, how do we calculate out,
有什么粗略的公式来计算每个循环应该移动多少 ?
what's the rough formula to figure
out how much we should move per loop?
让我们从开始开始吧
Well let's start with
let's start with elapsed.
我们想想过去有多少时间
Let's figure out how
much time has passed and
然后我们就可以用它来计算我们需要的距离
then we can use that to calculate
the distance that we need.
好的。
Okay.
到目前为止，我们所花的时间是相当的，现在是什么时候 ?
Pretty follow so far to get the elapsed
time we take, what time is it now?
我们什么时候开始
What time did we start?
4 点开始， 4 点 05分， 5 分钟已经过去了。
We started at 4 o'clock and
it's now 4:05, five minutes have elapsed.
这才是经过时间给我们的好吧
That's what elapsed time is gonna give us,
okay.
为了取得进步，这就是你的主要部分。
So to get the progress,
this is were the mathy part comes in.
Hm .
Hm.
我们可以说在总时间内耗用了多少时间。
We can say how much time has
elapsed over the total duration.
那么花费了多少时间与我们的时间有多大的比例
So what's the ratio of how much time
has been spent versus how much time we
想花花花去
want to spend.
这使我们取得了进展。
That gives us the progress.
到目前为止还好吗
Good so far?
这就是为什么如果你要找出动画循环
This is why, if you got to
figure out the animation loop,
我想说你做得非常好
I'd say you're doing pretty well so far.
最重要的是它变得有点棘手
The mathy part is where
it gets a little tricky.
老实说这就是我被人蔑视的地方
And honestly, this is where I got
flustered because I just got stuck and
我不知道数学是什么
I couldn't figure out the math part.
我只是在概念上无法做到
I just conceptually couldn't do it.
没关系我是说 会发生的
That's okay.
It's going to happen.
我觉得如果你表现得好的话，大多数的访问员都会好起来的。
I think if you demonstrate a good effort,
most interviewers will be like okay.
他们还没得到公式
They didn't get quite the formula but
如果他们有真正的编码他们可能会想出来的
if they had a real coding they
would probably figure this out.
就像你能把距离和那样的东西弄明白
Like you can figure out the distance and
the stuff like that.
接下来我们想弄清楚的是，我们想弄清楚这里发生了什么。
So next thing we want to figure out is,
we want to figure out what goes in here.
我们应该在每个回路上移动多少钱 ?
How much should we move
it on every single loop?
所以我就会打电话给你
So I'll call that amounts to move.
所以我们可以说，我们会想办法的。
And so for that we can say,
we'll figure out.
我们现在所取得的进展，基本上是一个已经过去的比率。
We have now the progress is essentially
a ratio of how much has elapsed.
因此，如果我们将这个比率乘以我们想要移动的距离。
So if we multiply that ratio times
the distance that we want to move.
我们能得到的
we can get, Yeah.
数学在概念上是微妙的。
The math is tricky conceptually.
所以说，好吧，我们得走了，五分钟已经过去了。
So it helps to say, all right,
we gotta last, five minutes have elapsed.
我只是用几分钟的时间来简单
I'm just using minutes cuz it's easier.
五秒已经过去了
Five seconds have elapsed.
因此，我们得到的是经过了多少时间和耗用了多少时间。
So we get the ratio of how much has
elapsed versus how much should elapse.
5 秒后，我们会说， 500 毫秒，那是什么 ?
So 5 seconds over, we'll say,
500 milliseconds, what is that?
那是 1%， 10%，好，等等，是 10%，对，好的。
That's 1%, 10%, okay, wait,
is that 10%, yes, okay.
别对我说
Don't judge me.
500 [ LAUGH] 500 以上
500 [LAUGH], 5 over 500.
好吧那是 1%
All right, so it's 1%.
所以在这一点上，我想要 1% 的距离，因为这就是要移动的程度。
So at this point I want 1% of the distance
because that's how much should be moving.
这就是以像素为单位移动的量。
And then that's the amount
to move in pixels.
好的，所以这都是关于改变你在这个特定场景下的想法的。
Okay, so it's all about changing your
thinking in this particular scenario.
我没有，我在数学上挂上了挂断。
I didn't, and
I got hung up on the math and it got me.
所以，我们还得在某个时候退出，因为如果不
So, we still need to exit at
some point because if we don't
穿过这么多的溪流我们可以继续
cross that many streams,
we can keep going over and
在不停地移动和移动的过程中
over and over to the keep moving and
moving and moving.
所以我可以说如果
So I can say if the amount to move is
比我们要移动的距离还要低然后再打一次
less than the distance that we're actually
supposed to move, then call it again.
一旦 ToMove ToshMove 过去了
And once that amountToMove has gone over,
它比距离还大，然后我们就不再称呼它了，我们完成了。
it's greater than the distance, then we
don't call it anymore, and we're done.
这就是如何使用 requestAnimationFrame 移动元素。
And that's how to move an element
using requestAnimationFrame.
当你这么做的时候它会很光滑的
And when you do it, it's gonna be very
smooth, it's gonna be like [SOUND] and
那就停了
then it's gonna stop.
如果你在想，我怎么才能让它快速移动呢 ?
Now if you're thinking,
how do I get it to move quickly?
然后我可以快速移动，就像放松
And then I can move it quickly,
which would be like easing
一些放松的功能让我们迅速地行动
some sort of easing function
that gives move quickly and
然后慢慢地慢慢地慢慢地动作
then slow down at the end or
start slow and move really quick.
我也不一定要你参加技术面试
Which, I wouldn't necessarily ask
you to in a technical interview, but
因为它的数学比较重
that's because it's more math heavy,
我们就会改变计算公式的方式
we would change how we calculate
this formula for the amount to move.
好吧好吧
All right, all right.
回家吧我们快到了
Home stretch, we're almost there.
干得好如果你能解决这件事真是太好了
Nice job, if you solved this one,
really good, this one's a little tricky.
但我想让你带走的主要部分是 requestAnimationFrame ，对于
But the main part I want you to take
away is requestAnimationFrame, for
做任何运动
doing any sort of movement.
有人说，哎，这东西是怎么画的呢 ?
Someone says, hey,
how do you animate this thing?
请说， requestAnimationFrame。
Just say, requestAnimationFrame.
你能不能用一个 for 循环来做，绝对的。
Could you do this in a for-loop,
absolutely.
会很顺利吗 ?
Will it be smooth, no.
这总是诡计，动作， requestAnimitionFrame。
That's always the trick,
movement, requestAnimationFrame.